{"test_questions": [[{"question": "How long is an IPv6 address?", "opta": "32 bits", "optb": "128 bytes", "optc": "64 bits", "optd": "128 bits", "ans": "D", "explanation": "An IPv6 address is 128 bits long."}, {"question": "What flavor of Network Address Translation can be used to have one IP address allow many users to connect to the global Internet?", "opta": "NAT", "optb": "Static", "optc": "Dynamic", "optd": "PAT", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Port Address Translation (PAT) allows a one-to-many approach to network address translation."}, {"question": "What are the two main types of access control lists (ACLs)?\n  Standard\n  IEEE\n  Extended\n  Specialized", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "3 and 4", "optd": "1 and 2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Standard and extended access control lists (ACLs) are used to configure security on a router."}, {"question": "What command is used to create a backup configuration?", "opta": "copy running backup", "optb": "copy running-config startup-config", "optc": "config mem", "optd": "wr mem", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The command to back up the configuration on a router is copy running-config startup-config."}, {"question": "You have 10 users plugged into a hub running 10Mbps half-duplex. There is a server connected to the switch running 10Mbps half-duplex as well. How much bandwidth does each \nhost have to the server?", "opta": "100 kbps", "optb": "1 Mbps", "optc": "2 Mbps", "optd": "10 Mbps", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Each device has 10 Mbps\tto the server."}, {"question": "Which WLAN IEEE specification allows up to 54Mbps at 2.4GHz?", "opta": "A", "optb": "B", "optc": "G", "optd": "N", "ans": "C", "explanation": "IEEE 802.11B is 2.4GHz, but with a maximum of only 11Mbps. IEEE 802.11G is in the 2.4GHz range, with a top speed of 54Mbps."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the valid host range for the subnet on which the IP address 192.168.168.188 255.255.255.192 resides?", "opta": "192.168.168.129-190", "optb": "192.168.168.129-191", "optc": "192.168.168.128-190", "optd": "192.168.168.128-192", "ans": "A", "explanation": "256 - 192 = 64. 64 + 64 = 128. 128 + 64 = 192. The subnet is 128, the broadcast address \nis 191, and the valid host range is the numbers in between, or 129-190."}, {"question": "To back up an IOS, what command will you use?", "opta": "backup IOS disk", "optb": "copy ios tftp", "optc": "copy tftp flash", "optd": "copy flash tftp", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The command copy flash tftp will prompt you to back up an existing IOS in flash to a TFTP host."}, {"question": "What protocol does PPP use to identify the Network layer protocol?", "opta": "NCP", "optb": "ISDN", "optc": "HDLC", "optd": "LCP", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Network Control Protocol is used to help identify the Network layer protocol used in the packet."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will allow you to set your Telnet password on a Cisco router?", "opta": "line telnet 0 4", "optb": "line aux 0 4", "optc": "line vty 0 4", "optd": "line con 0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The command line vty 0 4 places you in a prompt that will allow you to set or change your Telnet password."}, {"question": "Which protocol does DHCP use at the Transport layer?", "opta": "IP", "optb": "TCP", "optc": "UDP", "optd": "ARP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "User Datagram Protocol is a connection network service at the Transport layer, and DHCP uses this connectionless service."}, {"question": "Which command is used to determine if an IP access list is enabled on a particular interface?", "opta": "show access-lists", "optb": "show interface", "optc": "show ip interface", "optd": "show interface access-lists", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The show ip interface command will show you if any outbound or inbound interfaces have an access list set."}, {"question": "Where is a hub specified in the OSI model?", "opta": "Session layer", "optb": "Physical layer", "optc": "Data Link layer", "optd": "Application layer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Hubs regenerate electrical signals, which are specified at the Physical layer."}, {"question": "What does the passive command provide to dynamic routing protocols?", "opta": "Stops an interface from sending or receiving periodic dynamic updates.", "optb": "Stops an interface from sending periodic dynamic updates but not from receiving updates.", "optc": "Stops the router from receiving any dynamic updates.", "optd": "Stops the router from sending any dynamic updates.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The passive command, short for passive-interface, stops regular updates from being sent out an interface. However, the interface can still receive updates."}, {"question": "Which protocol is used to send a destination network unknown message back to originating hosts?", "opta": "TCP", "optb": "ARP", "optc": "ICMP", "optd": "BootP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "ICMP is the protocol at the Network layer that is used to send messages back to an originating router."}, {"question": "How often are BPDUs sent from a layer 2 device?", "opta": "Never", "optb": "Every 2 seconds", "optc": "Every 10 minutes", "optd": "Every 30 seconds", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Every 2 seconds, BPDUs are sent out from all active bridge ports by default."}, {"question": "How many broadcast domains are created when you segment a network with a 12-port switch?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "5", "optd": "12", "ans": "A", "explanation": "By default, switches break up collision domains but are one large broadcast domain."}, {"question": "What does the command routerA(config)#line cons 0 allow you to perform next?", "opta": "Set the Telnet password.", "optb": "Shut down the router.", "optc": "Set your console password.", "optd": "Disable console connections.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The command line console 0 places you at a prompt where you can then set your console user-mode password."}, {"question": "Which router command allows you to view the entire contents of all access lists?", "opta": "show all access-lists", "optb": "show access-lists", "optc": "show ip interface", "optd": "show interface", "ans": "B", "explanation": "To see the contents of all access lists, use the show access-lists command."}, {"question": "Which class of IP address has the most host addresses available by default?", "opta": "A", "optb": "B", "optc": "C", "optd": "A and B", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Class A addressing provides 24 bits for host addressing."}, {"question": "In a network with dozens of switches, how many root bridges would you have?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "5", "optd": "12", "ans": "A", "explanation": "You should have only one root bridge per network."}, {"question": "What PPP protocol provides dynamic addressing, authentication, and multilink?", "opta": "NCP", "optb": "HDLC", "optc": "LCP", "optd": "X.25", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Link Control Protocol in the PPP stack provides dynamic addressing, authentication, and multilink."}, {"question": "What is a stub network?", "opta": "A network with more than one exit point.", "optb": "A network with more than one exit and entry point.", "optc": "A network with only one entry and no exit point.", "optd": "A network that has only one entry and exit point.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Stub networks have only one connection to an internetwork. Only default routes can be set on a stub network or network loops may occur."}, {"question": "If your router is facilitating a CSU/DSU, which of the following commands do you need to use to provide the router with a 64000bps serial link?", "opta": "RouterA(config)#bandwidth 64", "optb": "RouterA(config-if)#bandwidth 64000", "optc": "RouterA(config-if)#clock rate 64", "optd": "RouterA(config-if)#clock rate 64000", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The clock rate command is two words, and the speed of the line is in bps."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is true regarding VLANs?", "opta": "Two VLANs are configured by default on all Cisco switches.", "optb": "VLANs only work if you have a complete Cisco switched internetwork. No off-brand switches are allowed.", "optc": "You should not have more than 10 switches in the same VTP domain.", "optd": "VTP is used to send VLAN information to switches in a configured VTP domain.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Switches do not propagate VLAN information by default; you must configure the VTP domain. VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) is used to propagate VLAN information across a trunk link."}, {"question": "What does a VLAN do?", "opta": "Acts as the fastest port to all servers.", "optb": "Provides multiple collision domains on one switch port.", "optc": "Breaks up broadcast domains in a layer 2 switch internetwork.", "optd": "Provides multiple broadcast domains within a single collision domain.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "VLANs break up broadcast domains at layer 2."}, {"question": "What is the main reason the OSI model was created?", "opta": "To create a layered model larger than the DoD model.", "optb": "So application developers can change only one layer's protocols at a time.", "optc": "So different networks could communicate.", "optd": "So Cisco could use the model.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The primary reason the OSI model was created was so that different networks could inter-operate."}, {"question": "How many collision domains are created when you segment a network with a 12-port switch?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "5", "optd": "12", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Layer 2 switching creates individual collision domains."}, {"question": "What command will display the line, protocol, DLCI, and LMI information of an interface?", "opta": "sh pvc", "optb": "show interface", "optc": "show frame-relay pvc", "optd": "show run", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The show interface command shows the line, protocol, DLCI, and LMI information of an interface."}, {"question": "Which protocol does Ping use?", "opta": "TCP", "optb": "ARP", "optc": "ICMP", "optd": "BootP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "ICMP is the protocol at the Network layer that is used to send echo requests and replies."}, {"question": "Which command is used to upgrade an IOS on a Cisco router?", "opta": "copy tftp run", "optb": "copy tftp start", "optc": "config net", "optd": "copy tftp flash", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The copy tftp flash command places a new file in flash memory, which is the default location for the Cisco IOS in Cisco routers."}, {"question": "If you wanted to delete the configuration stored in NVRAM, what would you type?", "opta": "erase startup", "optb": "erase nvram", "optc": "delete nvram", "optd": "erase running", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The command erase startup-config deletes the configuration stored in NVRAM."}, {"question": "What protocols are used to configure trunking on a switch?\n  VLAN Trunking Protocol\n  VLAN\n  802.1Q\n  ISL", "opta": "1 and 2", "optb": "3 and 4", "optc": "1 only", "optd": "2 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "VTP is not right because it has nothing to do with trunking except that it sends VLAN information across a trunk link. 802.1Q and ISL are used to configure trunking on a port."}]]}